♪Trapped in this tiny world♪
♪I'm crushed into dust♪
♪I meddle around without any mercy♪
♪I'm my own pawn♪
♪I sigh at my fate♪
♪Numerous people are under my control♪
♪All the sand is washed away♪
♪An old dream fades♪
♪A bumpy path lies ahead♪
♪Traps within traps, I never make mistakes♪
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪Even in disputes, I break through with my life♪
♪Schemes within schemes, I prison myself♪
♪Each link swaps bluff and truth♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
♪Everything's just fleeting♪
♪The play begins♪
♪No return is expected♪
♪The flame is gone, whether we win or lose♪
♪The wind never ceases. I hold the reins♪
[Ashes To Crown]
[Adapted from Xixing's novel, Empress of the State of Chu]
[Episode 23]
A group of Northern Desert killers
ambushed Jiu.
They chased Jiu for dozens of li
until he was cornered on a cliff
with no way out.
I heard he was seriously injured.
I guess he jumped off the cliff for the sake of dignity.
I swear on General Chu's armor.
I will stay alive
and return the armor.
Both.
The armor and me.
I give you my word.
I will come back alive.
Jiu,
you liar.
Why did you break your promise?
Your Highness!
Your Highness,
we received anonymous news.
Those killers aren't from
the Northern Desert
but Xiaonan Prefecture.
Xiao Xun declared himself king
and feared Yunzhong.
So, he wanted the Northern Desert King
to be a hostage.
Anyone who destabilizes my state
will be killed.
Issue my order.
All troops in Yunzhong stand ready for war.
I'll make Xiao Xun
pay blood for blood.
Great, no corpses were found.
The Northern Desert King died within this state.
Chu Zhao lost her sharpest blade too.
Tie Ying,
what expression
do you think she has now?
Xie Yanlai is dead.
The frontier troops will be demoralized.
Your Majesty,
a wise plan.
Wise?
That wasn't my plan.
I have to say
Xie Yanfang's trick
to find a scapegoat
was really brilliant.
Are you saying...?
He knew Chu Zhao would go mad.
He knew she would
blame me for everything.
However, Chu Zhao
focuses on fighting desperately
against me.
So, she might never realize
that she's being used.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
urgent report.
Her Highness led frontier troops
and broke through Qingyu Pass.
They're heading for Xiaonan.
At last, she's coming.
[Xiaonan]
Zhao,
why bother to make such a fuss?
You took your elite troops
to my prefecture.
Have you come to seek refuge with me?
Xiao Xun,
you rebelled,
murdered my general,
killed the enemy king,
and broke the alliance.
Today,
as the Grand Princess of State,
I'll punish the traitors!
I have the late Emperor's edict.
I'm the legitimate heir to the throne,
favored by heaven.
The real traitor
remains to be seen.
Faking an imperial edict
is an even greater offense.
Murdered your general?
Killed the enemy king?
You don't think
I killed Xie Yanlai, do you?
You always have an excuse to condemn me.
Chu Zhao,
for your personal revenge,
you're starting a war.
You killed a general
and brought chaos on the frontier.
How dare you say this is just an excuse?
Soldiers,
kill the traitors!
Kill!
- Kill! - Kill!
Xiao Xun has been captured.
You should all surrender!
Deng Yi,
how dare you...
I didn't expect that.
Deng Yi helped me win.
He also made me lose.
I'm the one who defeated you.
From now on,
you'll be the dowager.
Just enjoy a great life.
Oh, my silly son.
A mother
cares nothing for a great life.
All I want is that you can
stay safe.
This is the talisman I got for you.
You will stay healthy
and watch me
rise to a position
second only to the Emperor.
Chu Zhao had the talisman
sent to me.
She's threatening me.
Then what will you do, My Lord?
What can I do?
With this talisman,
she's warning me
that my mother is alive
and she has her.
Zhao,
I have true feelings for you.
I never meant to hurt you.
Is that so?
Then in my past life,
who strangled me
with white silk?
Your... Your past life?
Yes.
I lived once before.
I died too.
You killed me.
Why?
Why did you do this to my clan?
Why did you do this to me?
Why?
Are you scared?
In my past life,
when you massacred my clan
and cut off my father's head,
you weren't this cowardly.
What past life?
This is ridiculous.
How could anyone be reborn?
Zhao,
that must be a dream.
You can't hate me
for an illusory dream.
Zhao.
It wasn't a dream.
It was a purgatory
I truly experienced.
Illusory?
My pain was real.
My father's blood was real.
Zhao.
It was true
that all my clansmen suffered!
Zhao.
You never meant to hurt me?
You hated me badly
and wanted my father dead.
No.
You wanted my clan dead.
You only love the throne,
power,
and yourself.
Go to the underground
with your hypocrisy.
Xiao Xun,
for all the civilians
who suffered because of you...
For my father.
For Jiu.
And for me.
Xiao Xun,
you must die.
Xie Yanlai
wasn't killed...
In the third year of Xingping,
Xiao Xun, the Prince of Xiaonan,
got General Xie Yanlai killed.
He colluded with enemies,
trying to ruin the State of Chu!
As the Grand Princess,
I'm executing him to serve justice!
♪Trapped in this tiny world♪
♪I'm crushed into dust♪
♪I meddle around without any mercy♪
♪I'm my own pawn♪
♪I sigh at my fate♪
♪Numerous people are under my control♪
♪All the sand is washed away♪
♪An old dream fades♪
♪A bumpy path lies ahead♪
♪Traps within traps, I never make mistakes♪
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪Even in disputes, I break through with my life♪
♪Schemes within schemes, I prison myself♪
♪Each link swaps bluff and truth♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
♪Everything's just fleeting♪
You picked the wrong side.
A loser like me
won't argue.
You may die with ease.
Your mother is innocent.
I'll take care of her.
Your Highness, I beg you
not to tell her what becomes of me.
♪I follow my destined path♪
All right.
♪All the sand is washed away♪
♪An old dream fades♪
♪A bumpy path lies ahead♪
Your Highness,
thank you!
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
The Xiao Clan
will be reduced to commoners
and exiled to the frontier.
♪The play begins♪
♪No return is expected♪
♪The flame is gone♪
♪Whether we win or lose♪
[Xiaonan]
♪I hold the reins♪
Xie Yanlai
wasn't killed...
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
what's wrong?
Before Xiao Xun died,
he said he didn't kill Jiu.
Le,
is it possible that...?
That traitor was still deceitful
even before dying.
How could you believe him?
But I feel something is not right.
Your Highness,
you're overthinking.
Shall we rest early tonight?
Let me help you.
Your Highness,
Mr. Zhu is out there
with a report to make.
Show him in.
Greetings.
You asked me to investigate
the Wangcheng case.
We found
a suspicious merchant
named Yu Shang.
Go on.
He runs a small business
with little contact with big merchants.
But he's very friendly.
Many people in town
remember him.
When Yu Shang left the Capital,
he was holding a bottle of wine,
known as "Immortal Wine".
During those days, we searched
all the taverns and teahouses.
We even checked the banquets
of big clans.
It seemed an impossible job.
But we succeeded.
Those days, Yu Shang
went to some taverns.
In one of the taverns,
Liang Qiang was there.
More importantly,
a waiter witnessed
Yu Shang meeting Xie Yanfang
in a private room
on the second floor of Lianchi House.
Xie Yanfang?
Maybe that was a coincidence.
We're also carefully investigating
other guests who were there.
But too much time has passed.
We can't recover all details.
Not a coincidence.
He was involved with two key figures,
Yu Shang and Liang Qiang.
It couldn't be a coincidence.
I'm afraid everything was...
That was
a really marvelous plan.
Xiao Xun and Deng Yi are dead.
So is Xie Yanlai.
Now, the Grand Princess stands alone.
No threat.
You only need to seize her command
of the frontier troops.
And His Majesty trusts you.
Your position is secure,
as the ruler of the world.
For me,
controlling the game is what matters
more than being the ruler of the world.
Only those
blinded by hatred
would fail to see
such an obvious flaw.
I wonder
when the Grand Princess
will find out
that I am behind
all of this.
But by then,
she will have no choice
but to return to me.
General Liang,
how does it feel to be a prisoner
again?
What are you trying to say?
Just say it.
The day you got your title,
did you see Xie Yanfang?
I knew it.
At that banquet,
he toasted me from afar.
Only then did I know
he was the one who had been helping me
in the past few years.
I didn't know that before.
Didn't?
I...
At Xinggu Pass,
you let the enemy troops in
so that Wangcheng was lost
and your comrades died.
You didn't know?
You could have rejected the toast,
exposed his scheme,
or even have died in the battle
to prove loyalty.
But you chose
the dirtiest way.
I just wanted to make a name for myself.
The Xie Clan held great power.
If I rejected him...
You had countless chances
to turn back.
But after all,
you betrayed those
who trusted you.
Today,
I'll question you for the soldiers
who died unjustly.
How does it feel
to be promoted?
Soldiers in Wangcheng
never knew
their comrade had betrayed them
even before death.
I...
I've learned my lesson.
Liang Qiang killed himself last night.
He got what he deserved.
Jiu,
wait and see.
I will make him
pay for everything he has done.
Xie Yanfang always
has a backup plan.
The autumn hunt is coming.
He will bring this up
in the court.
On the day of the hunt,
he will make his move.
Then we should
make early preparations.
Your Highness...
Have the Longwei Army
ambush in the hunting ground.
This time,
I'll show him
how his trap
will be crushed.
Mr. Deng has just died.
His Majesty is young.
We need to make up for the Regent's absence.
I believe
Mr. Xie is the best choice.
- I second that. - I second that.
Mr. Xie is virtuous and talented.
He's worthy of this.
Your Highness works hard to command
the frontier troops.
I'll work together with you
to assist His Majesty.
The autumn hunt is coming.
Why don't we pray
for His Majesty during the hunt?
To hunt in this season,
I'm afraid...
When the late Emperor lived,
he loved the autumn hunt
to demonstrate our military might.
What do you think, Your Highness?
Mr. Xie,
it's a good idea.
Yu, don't be scared.
When you're around,
I won't be scared.
Even if I'm away
and you're all alone,
don't be scared.
Because you've grown up.
You can protect yourself
and you're the Emperor
who protects his people.
Come on, Yu.
Show me how well you can hunt.
Yu rides very well.
But he isn't good at archery.
An emperor doesn't need all skills.
He just needs to keep fit.
It's said you excel
in riding and archery.
Why don't you be his model?
Since Yu was little,
he has admired you.
All I seek in my life
is to help him become
an unparalleled emperor.
Whether I can be his model
and whether my clan
can remain unmatched...
Neither of those matters.
I know
you care for Yu
as well as our state.
For the court's long-term interests,
I want to issue a ban.
Ban imperial in-laws from official posts.
Mr. Xie,
what do you think?
Very good.
Don't you think this is hegemony?
In my heart,
you will help Yu
dominate the entire world.
But I don't think
this is hegemony.
It's what you should do
and what you have to do.
I pledge my life
to help you achieve this goal.
It has never changed.
In that case,
why did you kill my ally?
Who do you refer to? Deng Yi
or Zhong Changrong?
Or my brother Yanlai?
Deng Yi and I fell out
because of the loss of Wangcheng.
Or even earlier.
Because Deng Yi
insisted on appointing Liang Qiang.
But now it seems
that Liang Qiang was your mole.
So, Deng Yi
was within your plan.
That's right.
Liang Qiang has always
served me.
At Xinggu Pass,
if he had killed Zhong Changrong
and replaced him,
it would have saved me
a lot of trouble.
Sadly, Yanlai interfered.
My foolproof plan
ended in ruin.
So,
he had to die.
Then you sent your men
to kill him and the enemy king?
Xiao Xun was
a perfect scapegoat.
Why wouldn't I?
Xiao Xun killed the enemy king
and my brother Yanlai.
There was solid evidence.
That you massacred Xiaonan
to avenge Yanlai
is also known to all.
Now, even if you expose
the truth,
who would believe you?
I know.
Your Highness and Deng Yi
only differed in politics,
but you had to kill him yourself.
Deep in your heart,
you felt a little bit sad.
But the two of you
couldn't coexist in the court.
So for your own good,
Deng Yi had to die.
Even so,
you shouldn't have interfered.
I was helping you.
No need!
Xie Yanfang,
I'm not your plaything.
I'm different from those
you have tamed.
I won't become a puppet
under your control.
Don't think you've won.
Because this game
isn't over yet.
Unless I'm dead,
you can never command
the frontier troops.
You've already lost, Your Highness.
A ruler must not have weak spots.
You show mercy
to so many trivial people and things.
You're bound to lose.
Xie Yanfang,
what exactly do you want
from this trap of yours?
The frontier troops.
No way.
I'm not in a hurry.
Take your time to think it over.
But if you
insist on refusing,
tomorrow, the whole world will know:
"The Grand Princess was assassinated during the hunt
and before death,
Her Highness entrusted the Xie Clan with the military power."
Xie Yanfang,
you'll regret this.
Regret?
I won't regret anything.
Nor will you.
Du Qi.
Here.
Send Her Highness back to her tent.
She must be tired.
Yu,
this is venison from today's hunt.
Eat while it's hot.
Are you going to kill Zhao?
What makes you say that?
I'm young,
but I'm not stupid.
Zhao is confined.
There are unusual troop moves.
Do you really think
I know nothing?
Your Majesty,
I just want to show Her Highness
that some methods
just won't work.
If you can persuade Her Highness
to give me the Token,
I promise you.
She will be safe.
She's my sister!
The Grand Princess of State!
You...
Are you forcing me to make my choice?
You're wrong.
It's Her Highness who will make her own choice.
To keep the military power
or to keep alive.
I await your decision, Your Majesty.
Zhao,
I brought you some pastries.
Yu?
Why are you here?
It's cold at night.
You should have worn more.
Zhao,
are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Don't worry.
I don't want you to be confined.
Let's give the Token
to Uncle Yanfang.
Yu,
do you know the meaning
of the Frontier Troops Token?
Xie Yanfang represents the Xie Family.
If he seizes the military power
and allows his clan to dominate,
it will be a total disaster.
I just want you to live.
He promised me.
As long as you meet his conditions...
Don't worry.
We'll both be all right.
Someone will come to save us.
Who are you waiting for, Your Highness?
You guessed right.
The Longwei Army
is invincible.
They live incognito
and kill without a trace.
Sadly,
since you became the Grand Princess
and the Longwei Army turned up,
I have been investigating them.
It took me a lot of time.
But now,
I know who they are.
So, I cut off their heads
one after another
and took off the yellow ribbons
as proof of their identities.
You recognize this, don't you?
You monster!
Zhao!
You...
You will pay for this!
Me?
They all died because of you.
Not just them.
If you really disobey,
I'll also massacre Cangmu Stronghold
and bring you the heads
of Xiaoman and her men.
What do you say?
Your Highness,
Just admit your defeat.
Why don't you just kill me?
Then you will have
the court
and the frontier troops!
If you die,
Yu will be very sad.
Anyway,
I'm waiting for you
to surrender of your own will.
The frontier troops and Mr. Zhong
only obey this token.
This dagger is coated with Golden Finch Venom.
Xie Yanfang, you'll die!
Well, you've grown.
You've even learned to use poison.
There's no antidote for this poison.
Xie Yanfang,
you're going to die!
You would sacrifice your own life
just to kill me?
Yes!
I want you dead!
Zhao, run!
Your Majesty.
I order you
to drop your weapons!
This breaks my heart.
Seize her.
Dead or alive.
- Yes! - Yes!
Your Majesty.
Stop!
Don't run!
Catch her!
Stop!
Hurry!
Stop running!
Stop!
♪Broken walls and withered branches, trapped in the mire♪
♪Yet still striving to reach for the sky♪
♪My pride is torn down and my body is sacrificed♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪
♪Peril is everywhere in the palace♪
♪Yet I smile to nobody but you♪
♪Amidst the chaos♪
♪I'll always be with you♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪